in this video I'm going to talk about
one of the most misunderstood habit
structures when it comes to building
focus in your business for those of you
that I haven't met yet my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and for the last 21
years I have been building coaching and
mentoring businesses to over $10 million
a year and I want to help you whether
you're just starting out how to scale or
how to make the kind of money that you
want to make maybe you want to make 10
20 $30,000 per month it's going to take
a level of focus that's different than
anything else that maybe you've ever
experienced the first thing that we have
to realize is this is that when we talk
about Focus it's not about strain or
striving or stress it's actually more
about letting go because here's the
problem is that when we focus focus in
our brain like this and we're stressed
out about it it actually removes our
ability to cognitively function and do
things well and so I have a technique
that I actually use that helps me get in
the zone and focus when I'm struggling
to do so and it involves a combination
of a few different activities number
one I step into what I call CP mode what
is CP mode CP mode stands for childlike
play mode and what I do is I look at
what are activities or things that I
used to do when I was a kid that maybe I
got in trouble for or that I would do if
I had an unlimited amount of free time
that I would want to do now before you
log off of this video understand that
this is actually a strategy that has
helped make me seven figures and I have
actually proven this multiple times over
the last 10 years that this works I've
talked to multiple Millionaires and they
actually do this as part of their
strategy for focus and what it is is
that if you're struggling to focus we I
deal with this we have one activity that
we're doing over here and we want to
come into what we're doing in our
business and we're struggling to
actually do the things that we need to
do so what I do is I take a moment of
time no more than 15 to 30 minutes where
I will do something that's fun for me
reading a Sci-Fi novel might be one of
those things could also be playing a
video game just depend depends on what
the activity is that I need to focus on
afterwards I find if I'm making videos
like this reading tends to work better
if I'm doing something that's a bit more
technical on my computer such as
building a funnel or a landing page
video games tend to be a little bit
better for that okay and so what it is
is that I'm triggering myself out of the
thinking mind and into feeling and I'm
getting into a state of mind where I'm
letting go of all of the stuff that's
bothering me in my life temporarily as
far as that goes all that stuff is real
and we're not talking about negating
them or saying that we're going to
ignore them or not or or get rid of them
but we're shifting our Focus temporarily
for about 15 to 30 minutes off of those
things now this is where it gets fun
okay you got to like put a pause on that
because otherwise that's how you end up
as a dead beat and you're and you're not
doing anything that's worthwhile and uh
you know if I played video games all day
long I wouldn't have a great
relationship with my wife son or have a
good business you know as far as it goes
so after that what we do is we go
into what I call MF and no it doesn't
mean what you might think it means it
means meditative focus and so what I
will do is I will put on some music
because the music triggers a certain
thing and again it depends different
type of music for different type of
activities if I'm going to be cleaning
the house I might turn on some Latin
music if I'm going to be hanging out
with my my my wife I might turn on some
country music if I'm going to be doing
some video content like this I actually
just got done listening to while I did
my meditative Focus time The Cello Suite
from Johan Sebastian
Bach like that and I listened to that
and it got my brain while I closed my
eyes and went into a basically a 5minute
meditation I'm not talking about a 30
minute 5H hour meditation you know I
used to do those I downloaded the
headspace app years ago did the did the
long meditations now I've gotten to a
point where I have a a a multi-stage
process where I call meditative Focus so
I move out of the childlike play mode
which is temporary to shift out of the
stress the anxiety the uncertainty and
all of that into meditative Focus mode
and so what this is is where I will
close my eyes I'll usually sit down on a
couch or a chair I'll focus on my breath
and if I'm really really struggling I
might even go right into the place or
location where I have to do the activity
let's say that I'm really struggling to
make content in my business I did this
yesterday so I actually pulled up my
chair where I was going to make content
and sat down turned the lights on all of
that and then I went into my meditative
Focus time and here's what I do is I'll
focus on my breath this is stage one
I'll close my eyes focus on the breath
focus on my the the breath filling my
lungs right here okay and I'll do that
for about 5 to 10 seconds I'll I'll
really just shift my focus right here
here then I'll do a a what's called a
body scan where I will start mentally
imagining that I'm scanning from head to
toe imagine like you're dipping yourself
into water or coming out of water and
you can feel that sort of sensation you
can actually shift your focus from here
the breath to head
down down down down down to your toes
and then back up up up to the head and I
might do that three or three to five
times back and
forth and I'll do it not quickly but
I'll go like 10 seconds down 10 seconds
up while I'm still breathing and
focusing on the breath as well so I'm
almost now simultaneously focusing on my
breath which is kind of difficult to do
and this the body scan and generally
I'll stop focusing on the breath and go
right into the body scan as far as that
goes and then there's a moment where
I'll notice that I'm no longer thinking
or worrying about what's actually going
on and I'm just really focusing on being
present in my physical body here's the
next stage of this is that I start
to
visualize the activity that I'm about to
do so creating this content right here
and I actually got to a stage where I
realized just imagining or visualizing
myself creating the content wasn't
getting me into the zone that I needed
to get in and so what I started to do
was I started to while I was focusing on
the breath I would
visualize me having a great idea for
what I'm going to talk about in my video
because if I'm not if I'm making a piece
of content like
this maybe I I I was I was struggling
with lack of creativity of what I was
going to make a video about okay so I
went through I did I read a book for
about 15 minutes I did the meditative
Focus for about 5 minutes and then I
visualized for about 3 to five minutes
me having a great idea so you have to
understand the shift here with the
visualization and this is the part that
I think that a lot of people get wrong
with visualization that I'm going to
help you with right here okay so in my
present 3D reality right here this is
this is what I was experiencing right
here I
have I had no creativity no ideas I had
no um like like anything that I needed
to actually come up with a good video I
my mind was blank writer block as far as
that goes okay but in my visualization
which is separate from what I'm actually
experiencing I started to
imagine well what if I did have creative
ideas even though I don't even though I
wasn't even though I was experiencing
the writer Block in that moment or or
content creators block I visualized that
I had creative ideas even though I
actually didn't
in my mind I imagined what it would feel
like to have a creative idea and what
those would look like and the activity
of going into the visualization of doing
this and by the way these three stages
right here help you get here much
quicker in the creative process okay so
the childlike play moment where maybe
I'll either play a video game or I'll
I'll hang out with my son or I will read
a book or do something that's fun for me
that's not business focused
temporarily then I do the meditative
focus and then I visualize the thing
that I want to happen so I want to have
creativity and I had really no ideas or
even motivation to make a video like
this and all it took was just 5 minutes
of me sitting there to feel what it
would feel like to have creative ideas
what it would feel like to have
inspiration even though I didn't even
though I wasn't actually experiencing
that I imagined that I did and I allowed
my
imagination to actually see something in
my mind's eye that my reality did not
experience and what ended up happening
was my neurotransmitters because it's
all in my the lack of creativity really
is just the brain is blocked from being
able to experience that by visualizing
that I did have creativity
they started to come together and I
started to have creative ideas for what
I wanted to talk about in my video for
what I wanted to create a video about
and I found that this works in a number
of different parts of our life if I'm
struggling to come up with sales copy
for my offers if I'm struggling to come
up with ideas for my landing pages for
what I want to create in my business if
I'm struggling to even focus to be able
to
um do the dishes I'll tell you this it's
it's it sounds juvenile right why would
you need to focus on doing the dishes
well I
actually get some anxiety when I do the
dishes it's happened for about the last
years and there's a story behind that I
you know I think it comes to the fact
that I used to have an abusive roommate
that would actually verbally abuse me
for not doing the dishes and I've had to
process through that to where I
literally every time I go to do the
dishes I do it every night I I have
to it's a hard thing that I have to
learn to do the hard thing and I have to
visualize myself and break down the
steps of what it is that I'm doing so
I'm going to do I'm going to do the Cups
first I'm going to do the the the the
the pots and pans and even as I'm
talking about it it's hard for me to
articulate this just because I'm
still this is the first time in my life
that I've actually been able to break
out of the trigger I used to have dishes
they would pile up for week weeks on end
because of this trigger as far as that
goes and
so the fact that I'm able to utilize
visualization to
actually clean the house up every single
night without
anxiety is a huge thing and so if you
feel overwhelmed by certain activities
maybe you're overwhelmed by your
Facebook ads manager or the landing
pages or doing your taxes or whatever
that is if you can go through this three
stage process of the childlike play for
little bit of time maybe I'll even watch
something on Netflix that might help me
with that something to get you out of
the momentary strain or stress of what
is not working how you want it to in
your
mind when we get overwhelmed now we
don't want to get into the Habit where
we need to do this all the time here's
what's really cool is you're going to be
able to grow to where you don't need
that and all you need to do is to
trigger yourself into it is visualizing
yourself doing the activity and so in
the beginning when you're experiencing
the overwhelm you can step into the
childlike play moments you can do the
meditative focus and then you visualize
and then as you do that as that becomes
more comfortable and it starts to become
routine you can actually remove the
beginning steps you can remove the
playful moment and you just do the
meditative Focus then you can remove the
meditative focus when you don't need it
and you just visualize for about 5
minutes and then you can actually start
to visualize in the moment where you sit
down to do the thing that you want to do
and you start to visualize because
you're starting to wire your brain
cognitively to get into this moment it
starts to become a faster habit for you
you know how many times if you remember
a lot of this is like the overwhelm for
us of driving a car if do you remember
driving a car for the first time you had
to check your mirrors you had to do all
this stuff and it was overwhelming to do
that but now we do it on autopilot it's
because we've done it in enough times
that we've actually wired our brain to
where it creates a habit structure to
where we don't have to think about it
when we do it and that's where you want
to actually get to in your business and
in your life for the habits that are
healthy for you if you've ever noticed
that you might have habits that are
unhealthy for you you have trouble
breaking those habits it often is
because we've wired our brain to do
those things automatically as far as
that goes and so the best way to break a
habit is to actually visualize yourself
when you feel like you're also about to
do something that might be unhealthy for
you such as eating sugar I struggled
with sugar for a long time such as
alcohol you start to visualize in that
moment I'm really craving this thing you
visualize something else that you want
to replace it with in those moments and
for me I started doing that to where I
would exercise in the moments where I
was maybe craving sugar or things like
that you things that's crazy or you
could replace it with maybe I'm not
going to eat sugar but I might have a
protein shake or I might have a Bagel
you know again we might say well Bagel
sugar and bagel is actually going to be
better for you probably than processed
sugar most of the time as far as that
goes I'm not a I'm not a health coach as
far as that goes again eating less
processed foods more whole greens I it's
important and it's the best thing to do
for you as far as that goes this isn't a
health conversation right here anytime
that you feel overwhelmed with an
activity that you need to do to break
out of the overwhelm and to get into a
state of mind because it's about getting
into a state of mind that then sets you
up where your actions can follow in a
positive direction where you're no
longer
stuck I get stuck all the time in my
life and in my business and the way that
I get out of it is this three-stage
process that I talked about right here
and so I would encourage you to try it
out find an activity I've I've
encouraged people to do this for years
and I'm telling
you my coaching clients see results when
they do this like all the time where
they get into it's it's something that
is fun for them to do that is unrelated
to the activity it's a temporary mental
distraction you don't want to get caught
up in the distraction where now we get
addicted to it and that becomes our
habit every time we do it is that we run
to this thing to distract us that's the
negative side of it but you use a
temporary momentary distraction to
remove your focus from the overwhelm and
then you go back into calming the
nervous system down with the meditative
focus and then visualize yourself
actually doing the thing that was
overwhelming you and in my experience
and in my client's experience by doing
this it breaks us out of the cycle of
overwhelm and into peace and Clarity and
the ability to actually have fun doing
things that overwhelmed us for the
longest time you know for the longest
time me hanging out with my son was
something that really really overwhelmed
me to to my core it was very hard
I grew up I didn't have a dad till I was
like four or 5 years old and I didn't
know what it was like to be a dad and I
would literally have a hard time even
being around my son or spending time
with him and so what I had to learn how
to do is how to break myself out of the
mental overwhelm that I was experiencing
in those moments and so I've tested this
out in a number of different areas of my
life I'll even I'll even do it with
speed reading I've tried it out when I'm
reading a book I will visualize myself
speed reading the book and I will be
able to read faster because I'm wiring
my brain into a cognitive State that's
able to do something that seemed hard
for me now here's the part that I have
found which is interesting with the
speed reading is why I have these
three-stage process is if I only
visualize the speed reading I will
actually start to get a headache my
Vagas nerve will start to get tense and
so what I actually have to do is I have
to take the 5 minutes to meditate step
out of the stress and the anxiety to
calm the nervous system down and then
the visualization can actually come in
and be more effective and so this is why
if we're struggling to calm the nervous
system down these are three different
stages of tools that we can use
generally what I will try to do is this
as I as I reserve the childlike play
moment I reserve it for when this alone
doesn't work and this alone doesn't work
so what I have is a process now that
I've actually created where I go in
reverse order of this is that I will
actually start with the
visualization and if that doesn't work
after about 5 minutes I'll go
into a 5 minute meditation as far as
that goes and then I'll go back to
trying the visualization out if that
still doesn't work now I've spent about
15 minutes trying to do this now I know
okay this is a moment in time and I'll
make a note of it mentally that maybe
next time start with the childlike play
moment I found that out in over the last
week I was trying to create video
content it was taking me almost an hour
to get into the Zone just by meditating
or visualizing so now I added in for the
last couple of days the childlike play
moment beforehand which saved me over an
hour of time beforehand to now I do the
childlike play moment reading a book
reading a novel something like that
maybe playing a video game go into the
meditative moment go into the
visualization and the stress and anxiety
is reduced and and so this has allowed
me to actually become more productive
has allowed me to actually tap into
certain levels of creativity that I
didn't have before and have a lot more
confidence and feel great about what I'm
doing as far as that goes and so if we
look at these three different
stages I'll start with the visualization
if that doesn't work I'll do the
meditation and then I'll go into this
this moment right there okay so
hopefully this has helped you um break
past overwhelm you can apply this when
it comes to your business when it comes
to building your landing pages if you're
if you need to make webinars if you need
to write email content if you need to
write sales copy if you need to be able
to to do that and what it is is it's a
way of literally just rewiring your
brain to be able to do the things that
we find are difficult or hard and it
only takes about 15 minutes and it's a
it's a practice that I've actually found
really really works well for me uh
throughout my life and and I can look at
multiple millionaires that I've worked
with and they do the same thing as far
as that goes okay listen if you are a
coach trainer mentor and you want to
work with me on actually building your
business out and and go beyond just
these videos that we talk about hey
subscribe to the channel that'd be great
but also check out our accelerator
program I'd love to see you in there and
i' love I'd love to work with you to
help you build out your coaching
business or your course business to
create seven figures all right we'll
talk soon have a going everybody